I recently retired
تقاعدت مؤخراً
from the California Highway Patrol
من خفر طرقات كاليفورنيا
after 23 years of service.
بعد خدمة 23 سنة .
The majority of those 23 years
معظم تلك الفترة
was spent patrolling the southern end
قضيتها في دوريات في جنوب
of Marin County,
مقاطعة مارين .
which includes the Golden Gate Bridge.
والذي يشمل جسر البوابة الذهبية .
The bridge is an iconic structure,
الجسر عبارة عن مبنى إبداعي ،
known worldwide
معروف على مستوى العالم
for its beautiful views of San Francisco,
بمنظره الجمالي لسان فرانسيسكو ،
the Pacific Ocean, and its inspiring architecture.
والمحيط الهادي ، وبهندسته الملهمة .
Unfortunately, it is also a magnet for suicide,
للأسف ، هو أيضاً عامل جذب للانتحار ،
being one of the most utilized sites in the world.
حيث يعد من أكثر المناطق في العالم محاولة للانتحار .
The Golden Gate Bridge opened in 1937.
افتتح جسر البوابة الذهبية عام 1937 .
Joseph Strauss, chief engineer in charge of building the bridge,
جوزيف ستراوس ، رئيس المهندسين ، المسؤول عن بناء الجسر
was quoted as saying,
اقتبس عنه وهو يقول ،
"The bridge is practically suicide-proof.
" الجسر عملياً مضاد للانتحار .
Suicide from the bridge
الانتحار من على الجسر
is neither practical nor probable."
ليس عملياً وليس ممكناً. "
But since its opening,
لكن من حين افتتاحه
over 1,600 people have leapt to their death
أكثر من 1600 شخص قفزوا لحتفهم
from that bridge.
من على ذلك الجسر .
Some believe that traveling
البعض يعتقد بأن السفر
between the two towers
بين برجي الجسر
will lead you to another dimension --
سيؤدي بهم إلى بُعد آخر ،
this bridge has been romanticized as such —
هذا الجسر يحمل فكرة رومنسية
that the fall from that
وكأن السقوط من عليه
frees you from all your worries and grief,
سيحررك من آلامك وأحزانك ،
and the waters below
والماء في الأسفل
will cleanse your soul.
سيغسل روحك .
But let me tell you what actually occurs
لكن دعوني أخبركم بما يحدث فعلاً
when the bridge is used
عندما يستخدم الجسر
as a means of suicide.
بنية الإنتحار .
After a free fall of four to five seconds,
بعد السقوط الحر بأربع أو خمس ثوان ،
the body strikes the water
يرتطم الجسم بالماء
at about 75 miles an hour.
بسرعة تصل إلى 75 ميل في الساعة .
That impact shatters bones,
تلك الصدمة تهشم العظام ،
some of which then puncture vital organs.
التي تخترق بعد ذلك الأعضاء الحيوية ،
Most die on impact.
الكثير يموتون من أثر الارتطام .
Those that don't
أما الذين لا يموتون
generally flail in the water helplessly,
فهم بشكل عام يطفون بلا حول ولا قوة ،
and then drown.
وبعدها يغرقون .
I don't think that those who contemplate
لا أعتقد بأن الذين اختاروا
this method of suicide
هذه الطريقة في الانتحار
realize how grisly a death that they will face.
يدركون كم هو مروع الموت بهذه الطريقة .
This is the cord.
هذا هو الرباط .
Except for around the two towers,
باستثناء الأربطة حول البرجين ،
there is 32 inches of steel
هناك 32 بوصة من الحديد
paralleling the bridge.
موازية للجسر .
This is where most folks stand
هنا يقف أغلب هؤلاء الأشخاص
before taking their lives.
قبل أن يقتلوا أنفسهم .
I can tell you from experience
ومن خبرتي أستطيع القول
that once the person is on that cord,
بأن الشخص لو وصل إلى ذلك الرباط ،
and at their darkest time,
وفي أحلك لحظات حياته ،
it is very difficult to bring them back.
فمن الصعب جداً أن تستعيده .
I took this photo last year
إلتقطت هذه الصورة العام لماضي
as this young woman spoke to an officer
بينما كانت هذه الشابة تتحدث مع الضابط
contemplating her life.
وهي تتأمل حياتها .
I want to tell you very happily
وأستطيع أن أقول لكم بسعادة
that we were successful that day
أننا استطعنا بنجاح ذلك اليوم
in getting her back over the rail.
أن نستعيدها من على السياج .
When I first began working on the bridge,
عندما بدأت في العمل على الجسر ،
we had no formal training.
لم نكن مدربين تدريباً رسمياً .
You struggled to funnel your way through these calls.
كنا نعاني في تلبية هذه النداءات
This was not only a disservice
لم يكن الأمر سيئاً فقط
to those contemplating suicide,
لمن يحاول الانتحار ،
but to the officers as well.
بل للضباط أيضاً .
We've come a long, long way since then.
لقد قطعاً شوطاً طويلاً منذ ذلك الحين .
Now, veteran officers and psychologists
الآن ، الضباط القدامى والأخصايين النفسيين
train new officers.
يدربون الضباط الجدد .
This is Jason Garber.
هذا هو جيسون غاربر .
I met Jason on July 22 of last year
ألتقيت جيسون في 22 يونيو من العام الماضي
when I get received a call
عندما استلمت نداء
of a possible suicidal subject
بحالة يشتبه أنها محاولة إنتحار
sitting on the cord near midspan.
جالساً على الرباط في منتصف الجسر .
I responded, and when I arrived,
استجبت ، وعندما وصلت ،
I observed Jason
راقبت جيسون
speaking to a Golden Gate Bridge officer.
وهو يتحدث مع ضابط الجسر
Jason was just 32 years old
كان جيسون يبلغ 32 عاماً من العمر
and had flown out here from New Jersey.
وقد جاء بالطائرة من نيو جيرسي .
As a matter of fact,
في الواقع ،
he had flown out here on two other occasions
لقد أتى إلى هنا مرتين قبل هذه المرة
from New Jersey
من نيو جيرسي
to attempt suicide on this bridge.
لمحاولة الإنتحار من فوق هذا الجسر .
After about an hour of speaking with Jason,
بعد حوالي الساعة من التحدث إلى جيسون ،
he asked us if we knew the story of Pandora's box.
سأل اذا ما كنا نعرف قصة صندوق باندورا .
Recalling your Greek mythology,
لو تذكرون في الأسطورة الإغريقية ،
Zeus created Pandora,
زيوس خلق باندورا ،
and sent her down to Earth with a box,
وأرسلها إلى الأرض مع صندوق ،
and told her, "Never, ever open that box."
ثم أخبرها ، "بأن لا تفتح الصندوق أبداً ."
Well one day, curiosity got the better of Pandora,
لكن في يوم ما ، تمكن الفضول من باندورا ،
and she did open the box.
ودفعها إلى فتح الصندوق .
Out flew plagues, sorrows,
فانطلقت منه الطواعين والأحزان ،
and all sorts of evils against man.
وكل أنواع الشر ضد البشر .
The only good thing in the box was hope.
الخير الوحيد في ذلك الصندوق كان الأمل .
Jason then asked us,
بعدها سأَلنا جيسون ،
"What happens when you open the box
" ماذا سيحدث لو فتحت الصندوق
and hope isn't there?"
ولم يكن هنالك أمل ؟ "
He paused a few moments,
صمت بعدها للحظات ،
leaned to his right,
ومال على يمينه ،
and was gone.
ثم رحل .
This kind, intelligent young man from New Jersey
هذا الشاب الحنون ، الذكي من نيو جيرسي
had just committed suicide.
أقدم للتو على الإنتحار .
I spoke with Jason's parents that evening,
تحدث مع أبوي جيسون في تلك الليلة ،
and I suppose that, when I was speaking with them,
وأعتقد أنني وأثناء حديثي معهم ،
that I didn't sound as if I was doing very well,
لم أبدو وكأنني قد عملت كل مافي وسعي ،
because that very next day,
لأنه وفي اليوم التالي ،
their family rabbi called to check on me.
اتصل حَبر الأسرة ليتحقق مني .
Jason's parents had asked him to do so.
أبوا جيسون طلبوا منه فعل ذلك .
The collateral damage of suicide
الضرر الغير المباشر للإنتحار
affects so many people.
يأثر على أناس كثيرين .
I pose these questions to you:
سأطرح عليكم هذا السؤال :
What would you do if your family member,
ماذا ستفعلون لو كان أحد أفراد أسرتكم
friend or loved one was suicidal?
أصدقاءكم ومن تحبون يحاول الإنتحار ؟
What would you say?
ماذا ستقولون ؟
Would you know what to say?
كيف ستعرفون ما ستقولونه ؟
In my experience, it's not just the talking that you do,
حسب خبرتي ، فإنه ليس فقط بالتحدث
but the listening.
وإنما بالإنصات .
Listen to understand.
أنصت لتفهم .
Don't argue, blame,
لا تحاجج ، ولا تلوم ،
or tell the person you know how they feel,
لا تخبر ذلك الشخص بأنك تشعر به ،
because you probably don't.
لأنك على الأغلب لا تشعر .
By just being there,
فقط بتواجدك هناك ،
you may just be the turning point that they need.
قد تكون نقطة التحول التي يحتاجون إليها .
If you think someone is suicidal,
اذا ما أحسست بأن شخص يفكر بالإنتحار ،
don't be afraid to confront them and ask the question.
لا تخشى بأن تواجهه وتسأله عن ذلك .
One way of asking them the question is like this:
أحد طرق طرح هذا السؤال كالتالي :
"Others in similar circumstances
" أشخاص آخرون في ظروف مشابهة
have thought about ending their life;
فكروا في إنهاء حياتهم ؛
have you had these thoughts?"
هل خطرت في بالك مثل هذه الأفكار ؟"
Confronting the person head-on
مواجهة الشخص مباشرةً
may just save their life and be the turning point for them.
قد تنقذ حياته وتكون نقطة تحول بالنسبة له .
Some other signs to look for:
بعض الإشارات الآخرى التي يمكنك ملاحظتها :
hopelessness, believing that things are terrible
اليأس ، الاعتقاد بأن الحياة مرعبة
and never going to get better;
وأنها لن تتحسن أبداً ؛
helplessness, believing that there is nothing
العجز ، الاعتقاد بأنه لا يوجد شئ
that you can do about it;
تستطيع فعله حيال الأمر ؛
recent social withdrawal;
الانسحاب من الحياة الإجتماعية ؛
and a loss of interest in life.
وفقدان الرغبة في الحياة .
I came up with this talk just a couple of days ago,
خطر لي هذا الحديث قبل عدة أيام ،
and I received an email from a lady
بعدما وصلني بريد إلكتروني من سيدة
that I'd like to read you her letter.
أرغب في قراءة رسالتها لكم
She lost her son on January 19 of this year,
فقدت ابنها في 19 من يناير هذا العام ،
and she wrote this me this email
فأرسلت لي هذا البريد
just a couple of days ago,
فقط قبل عدة أيام ،
and it's with her permission and blessing
وبعد موافقتها ومباركتها
that I read this to you.
سأقرأ عليكم .
"Hi, Kevin. I imagine you're at the TED Conference.
" مرحباً ، كيفن . أتوقع أنك في مؤتمر TED الآن .
That must be quite the experience to be there.
لابد أن التواجد هناك يعد تجربة رائعة .
I'm thinking I should go walk the bridge this weekend.
أفكر في أنه يفترض بي أن أسير على الجسر نهاية الأسبوع .
Just wanted to drop you a note.
فأردت أن أترك لك ملاحظة .
Hope you get the word out to many people
آملةً بأن توصل كلمتي للناس
and they go home talking about it
فيعودون لبيوتهم ويخبرون عنها
to their friends who tell their friends, etc.
أصدقاءهم الذين يخبرون أصدقاءهم ، إلخ .
I'm still pretty numb,
مازلت فاقدة للاحساس بعض الشئ ،
but noticing more moments of really realizing
لكن بدأت بالفعل في إدراك تلك اللحظات
Mike isn't coming home.
بأن مايك لن يعود للمنزل .
Mike was driving from Petaluma to San Francisco
كان مايك يقود سيارته من بيتالوما باتجاه سان فرانسيسكو
to watch the 49ers game with his father
ليشاهد مباراة فريق سان فرانسيسكو 49 مع والده
on January 19.
في 19 من يناير .
He never made it there.
لكنه لم يصل إلى الأبد .
I called Petaluma police
اتصلت بشرطة بيتالوما
and reported him missing that evening.
وأبلغت عن فقدانه في تلك الليلة .
The next morning,
وفي الصباح التالي ،
two officers came to my home
أتى ضابطان إلى منزلي
and reported that Mike's car was down at the bridge.
وأبلغوني بأن سيارة مايك كانت واقفة بالقرب من الجسر
A witness had observed him jumping off the bridge
وقد لاحظه شاهد عيان وهو يقفز من على الجسر
Thanks so much
شكراً جزيلاً لك
for standing up for those
لمساندة أولائك الذين
who may be only temporarily too weak
كانوا فقط ولفترة مؤقتة ضعفاء جداً
Who hasn't been low before
من منا لم يشعر بالضعف
without suffering from a true mental illness?
حتى بدون المعاناة من مرض نفسي ؟
It shouldn't be so easy to end it.
إنه لمن الصعب جداً القضاء عليه .
My prayers are with you for your fight.
دعائي لك في كفاحك .
The GGB, Golden Gate Bridge,
جسر البوابة الذهبية ،
is supposed to be a passage across
كان يفترض أن يكون المعبر
our beautiful bay,
لخليجنا الجميل ،
not a graveyard.
وليس مقبرة .
Good luck this week. Vicky."
أمنياتي لك بالتوفيق هذا الأسبوع ، فيكي. "
I can't imagine the courage it takes for her
لا أستطيع تصور شجاعتها
to go down to that bridge and walk the path
بأن تذهب للمشي فوق الجسر وتسير في الطريق
and also the courage just to carry on.
وشجاعتها فقط في مواصلة الحياة .
I'd like to introduce you to a man
أريد أن أعرفكم على رجل
I refer to as hope and courage.
أصفه بالأمل والشجاعة .
On March 11 of 2005,
في 11 من مارس 2005 ،
I responded to a radio call of a possible
أستجبت لنداء على الراديو بما يحتمل انه
suicidal subject on the bridge sidewalk
محاولة انتحار على ممر المشاة الجانبي
near the north tower.
قرب البرج الشمالي .
I rode my motorcycle down the sidewalk
قدت دراجتي النارية على ممر المشاة
and observed this man, Kevin Berthia,
ولاحظت ذلك الرجل ، كيفن بيرثيا ،
standing on the sidewalk.
يقف على ممر المشاة الجانبي .
When he saw me, he immediately traversed
عندما رآني ، اجتاز مباشرة
that pedestrian rail,
حاجز المشاة ،
and stood on that small pipe
ووقف على ذلك الأنبوب الصغير
For the next hour and a half,
وطوال الساعة والنصف التالية ،
I listened as Kevin spoke about
أنصت إلى كيفن وهو يتكلم
his depression and hopelessness.
عن اكتئابه ويأسه .
Kevin decided on his own that day
كيفن قرر في ذلك اليوم
to come back over that rail
أن يرجع من على ذلك الحاجز
and give life another chance.
ويعطي حياته فرصة آخرى .
When Kevin came back over,
عندما رجع كيفن ،
I congratulated him.
هنأته .
"This is a new beginning, a new life."
"هذه بداية جديدة ، هذه حياة جديدة."
But I asked him, "What was it
لكني سألته ، " ماذا كان السبب
that made you come back
الذي جعلك تعود من جديد
and give hope and life another chance?"
وتعطي الحياة والأمل فرصة آخرى ؟"
And you know what he told me?
أتعلمون ماذا قال لي ؟
He said, "You listened.
لقد قال ، " أنك أنصت إلي .
You let me speak, and you just listened."
تركتني أتحدث ، وفقط أنصت إلي . "
Shortly after this incident,
بعد الحادثة بفترة قصيرة ،
I received a letter from Kevin's mother,
استلمت رسالة من أم كيفن ،
and I have that letter with me,
وهاهي الرسالة معي الآن ،
and I'd like to read it to you.
وأود قراءتها عليكم .
"Dear Mr. Briggs,
" عزيزي السيد بريقز،
Nothing will erase the events of March 11,
لا شئ سيمحو ما حدث في 11 من مارس ،
but you are one of the reasons Kevin is still with us.
لكنك أحد أسباب بقاء كيفن معنا الآن .
I truly believe Kevin was crying out for help.
أوقن تماماً بأن كيفن كان يستغيث للنجدة
He has been diagnosed with a mental illness
لقد تم تشخيصه بمرض نفسي
for which he has been properly medicated.
يتعالج منه الآن بانتظام .
I adopted Kevin when he was only six months old,
لقد تبنيت كيفن عندما كان عمره 6 أشهر ،
completely unaware of any hereditary traits,
ولم أكن أعلم إطلاقاً بصفاته الموروثة ،
but, thank God, now we know.
لكن والشكر لله ، نحن نعلم ذلك الآن .
Kevin is straight, as he says.
كيفن استقام كما يقول .
We truly thank God for you.
نحن نحمد الله حقاً لوجودك .
Sincerely indebted to you,
المخلصة والمدينة لك ،
Narvella Berthia."
نارفيلا بيرثيا. "
And on the bottom she writes,
وفي أسفل الرسالة كتبت ،
"P.S. When I visited San Francisco General Hospital that evening,
" هامش ، عندما زرت مستشفى سان فرانسيسكو العام في تلك الليلة ،
you were listed as the patient.
كانوا قد كتبوا اسمك على أنك المريض .
Boy, did I have to straighten that one out."
أقسم أنني أردت وبشدة تصحيح ذلك الخطأ ."
Today, Kevin is a loving father
اليوم ، كيفن أصبح أبٌ حنون
and contributing member of society.
وعضو فعال في المجتمع .
He speaks openly
يتحدث بصراحة
about the events that day and his depression
عن أحداث ذلك اليوم وعن اكتئابه
in the hopes that his story
على أمل أن قصته
will inspire others.
تلهم الآخرين .
Suicide is not just something I've encountered on the job.
الانتحار ليس مجرد شئ واجهته أثناء عملي .
It's personal.
أنه شئ شخصي .
My grandfather committed suicide by poisoning.
جدي أقدم على الانتحار بتسميم نفسه .
That act, although ending his own pain,
مع أن ذلك الفعل قد أنهى ألمه الخاص ،
robbed me from ever getting to know him.
لكنه سلبني فرصة التعرف عليه .
This is what suicide does.
هذا ما يفعله الانتحار .
For most suicidal folks,
أغلب المنتحرين ،
or those contemplating suicide,
أو من يفكرون بالانتحار ،
they wouldn't think of hurting another person.
لا ينوون إيذاء شخص آخر .
They just want their own pain to end.
يريدون فقط إنهاء ألمهم الخاص .
Typically, this is accomplished in just three ways:
عادةً ، يتم تحقيق ذلك بثلاث طرق :
sleep, drugs or alcohol, or death.
بالنوم ، بالمخدرات أو الكحول أو إما بالموت .
In my career, I've responded to
أثناء عملي ، استجبت
and been involved in hundreds
وشاركت في المئات
of mental illness and suicide calls
من نداءات محاولة الانتحار والأمراض النفسية
around the bridge.
حول الجسر .
Of those incidents I've been directly involved with,
وتلك الحوادث التي كنت المسؤول المباشر فيها
I've only lost two,
فقدت فيها فقط حالتين ،
but that's two too many.
لكن حالتين تعتبر كثيرة .
One was Jason.
واحدوة منها كانت جيسون .
The other was a man I spoke to
والآخرى كانت لرجل تكلمت معه
for about an hour.
حوالي الساعة .
During that time, he shook my hand
وأثناء حديثي معه ، صافح يدي
on three occasions.
ثلاث مرات .
On that final handshake,
عند المصافحة الأخيرة ،
he looked at me, and he said,
نظر إلي ، وقال ،
"Kevin, I'm sorry, but I have to go."
" كيفن ، أنا آسف ، لكن علي الذهاب . "
And he leapt.
وقفز بعدها .
Horrible, absolutely horrible.
مرعب ، مروع تماماً
I do want to tell you, though,
أريد أن أخبركم أيضاً ،
the vast majority of folks
أن الغالبية العظمى من الناس
that we do get to contact on that bridge
الذين نلتقيهم على ذلك الجسر
do not commit suicide.
لا يقدمون على الانتحار
Additionally, that very few
بالإضافة أيضاً ، أولئك القلة
who have jumped off the bridge and lived
الذين قفزوا من على الجسر وعاشوا
and can talk about it,
واستطاعوا التكلم عن تجربتهم ،
that one to two percent,
تلك الواحد أو الاثنان بالمئة ،
most of those folks have said
قال أغلبهم
that the second that they let go of that rail,
أنه وفي تلك اللحظة التي اجتازوا فيها ذلك الحاجز
they knew that they had made a mistake
علموا أنهم قد ارتكبوا خطأً
and they wanted to live.
وأرادوا العيش مرة آخرى .
I tell people, the bridge not only connects
ما أقوله للناس ، أن الجسر لا يصل فقط
Marin to San Francisco,
مارين بسان فرانسيسكو
but people together also.
لكنه يصل الناس ببعضها أيضاً .
That connection, or bridge that we make,
ذلك الاتصال أو الجسر الذي نكوّنه ،
is something that each and every one of us
لهو شئ يجب على كل واحد منا
should strive to do.
أن يناضل من أجله .
Suicide is preventable.
الانتحار يمكن الوقاية منه .
There is help. There is hope.
هناك مساعدة ، هناك أمل .
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم .
(Applause)
( تصفيق )